The card payment [music] interface is
the singular best user interface ever
created. It is the world's largest
market [music] by any stretch of
imagination. And there are no niches and
payments that are smaller than hund00
billion.
>> Once you go really big, the numbers get
small, which is strange. [music] There's
a lot of volume, but the large volume
revenue opportunities and payments tend
to be the smaller dollar amounts.
>> There's always an opportunity to use
another form of payment delivery device
to satisfy a basic need. convenience
just trumps as the total amount you're
trying to send goes down. The best user
interface ever created is the credit
card. This may [music] actually be
finally up for renegotiation because AI
is already there. It's just that you
haven't yet trusted your agent to do as
good a job as you would. There is
something else that you're surprised has
not happened yet. I went to some
cryptography related conference and
presented a new idea in digital payments
and was literally booed off stage
because it was certainly not anonymous
and the the big innovation of PayPal was
what if we don't care about anonymity at
all and in [music] that sense um
so you guys go way back having co-ounded
a firm and and met well before then you
guys are pioneers in in fintech you've
been thinking about the space trying to
make sense of the present you know think
about where the future is going for 20
plus years, 25 years, maybe even more.
And I'm curious, you know, given so much
time has passed since you first got into
the space, what has most surprised you
about what has happened, what hasn't
happened, what did you expect to happen
in the early 2000s of how how this space
would would play out? Maybe Alex, why
don't you start? I think the rise of
Apple Pay and Google Pay and to the
extent the the extent to which they've
really penetrated because it's very hard
to change consumer behavior in general
and it was a bizarre set of accidents if
you will where there is this merchant
liability shift because magst stripes
were so easy to replicate that uh you
probably noticed a while ago you your
new cards had a little chip on them and
you had to dip the chip and then the
machine would be like you know don't
remove don't remove right that's because
the chip was being rewritten it was much
more secure than a magstripe and
basically Visa and Mastercard. Um, and
then the Euro Pay that's what the E is
for. Uh, but what is EU for? EMV.
>> Europe card.
>> Euro card.
>> I don't know. The Europeans somehow got
their say because they always do. They
they insert their not electronic. That's
>> Yeah, it's it's euro something
Mastercard Visa. So, it was it was
called the EMV switch. So, all of these
machines, if you did not want to be
liable, um, like I could go to Best Buy,
buy a TV, and then get home, use my TV,
and say, "Nope, never bought the TV."
And if I was using my magstripe and Best
Buy didn't have the the machine switch
over, then Best Buy would be like, "Oh,
shoot. We lost all the money on that TV,
and Alex gets the free TV." I'm
exaggerating slightly for a fact. So,
everybody had to get a new machine. And
then it turned out that those new
machines had a little contactless, you
know, thing where you didn't have to dip
the chip or swipe the card. You could
just tap. Nobody was using taps when
those machines came out and now it's
ubiquitous. So that's that's something
where I mean generally speaking it's
hard to change consumer behavior but I
feel like between COVID and the fact
that all these merchants independently
had to switch over their machines and
the fact that I mean I wouldn't have
guessed in I mean you obviously did
because the uh confinity was was Palm
Pilot sending money. So you you're ahead
of the whole PDA wave but I wouldn't
have guessed that those three things
would have come behavior. It's like
change of of consumer behavior,
ubiquitous new merchant payment terminal
plus ubiquitous uh mobile telefan and
that's that's certainly one thing that
has changed the world a lot.
>> How about you Max? You you were dreaming
about you know what what the future of
money would look like a long time ago.
Would it have surprised you about what
has happened or what hasn't happened?
It's very hard to uh step back from the
soup if you're cooking in it uh for the
last plus or minus 30 odd years.
Uh, I think the to sort of further
illustrate Alex's point, one of the
things that's really amazing and subtle
about Apple Pay/Google Pay and its
interaction with the Visa Mastercard
networks is Visa and Mastercard have a
hard 2 and a half second limit on
interaction between the network, the
issuing bank and the merchant and the
acquiring bank. And so the whole thing
has to happen in 10 seconds where the
transaction gets retrieded or maybe just
canceled out and really leaves very
little room for any kind of clever
innovation. And online you can play
games. If you're doing e-commerce you're
like well yes we're going to submit your
card to Visa but first we're going to
run some anti- fraud checks and we're
going to do some other things to like
reduce liability.
But offline like once your card is
presented two and a half seconds that's
all you got. And Google and Apple Pay
have singularly timeshifted the whole
thing by creating secure enclaves inside
their chips and saying I already know
your card. I can do all kinds of things
before I actually have to talk to Visa
Mastercard. And maybe the shocking thing
is that Visa Mastercard have not yet
introduced some new standards saying
actually it doesn't have to be two and a
half seconds at all. It could be 15
seconds while we know go and get a bunch
of issuers to bid on a better credit
quality terms for you or any other type
of innovation.
the sort of hardwritten rules of dehawk
era are more or less intact and that's
not 30 years that's like more you know
60 years and so I think that's probably
a critical or more criticizing take on
what happened um
but the shocking thing about payments is
that it is the world's largest market by
any stretch of imagination and
anything and everything you could have
possibly thought of being sort of
deconstructed and being the nichiest
little thing to poke around and innovate
in always turns out to be a hundred
billion dollar. There are no niches and
payments that are smaller than hundred
billion. And so that's probably the most
surprising thing I've seen.
>> Yeah.
>> Although it's interesting like once you
go really big, the numbers get small,
which is strange, right? Like if I send
a $1 trillion wire, right? The United
States just announced we we are $40
trillion in debt, right? Let's just say
that like, you know, Elon's Mars colony
is worth $40 trillion. and you know
Roana decides to tax him $40 trillion
and he needs to send a wire that wire is
not going to be very pro like there
there's a lot of volume but the large
volume revenue opportunities and
payments tend to be the smaller dollar
amounts um which is surprising right
because it turns out I mean like all of
the QSR the quickserve restaurant the
payment opportunity there that's massive
that's why Starbucks invented Starbucks
pay because they wanted to stop having
to pay it's like these prepaid they only
have to pay one time. You char you put
$50 on your Starbucks account. Well,
they only have to pay Visa, Mastercard,
and everybody else one time as opposed
to every successive time. So, a lot like
what's surprising about payment uh area
under the curve, if you will, is that
like the bigger the dollars, like the
smaller the rake, which I guess makes
sense because you're not going to get 2%
of that $40 trillion payment, but
everybody goes after B2B payments.
Everybody has a clever idea for B2B
payments and like that's the only one
that is probably the exception to the
rule. I was trying to find so it's lost
in time the original email between the
two of us which I think we have slightly
different origin stories of how we
actually met
>> but I was trying to find the original
email between the two of us where we
start mentioning what becomes a firm
eventually and it's dated
April 2011
and uh in it
I think I ask you like tell me more
about this bill me later thing because I
was working on something else while you
were watching PayPal buying build me and
you send me these really long elaborate
sort of here's exactly what it is and
all these ideas around it and we then
veer off into this ping pong of emails
around bill me later for business and
conclude that it's actually a dumb
business where there's there isn't an
opportunity
>> well and that's actually it's funny you
mentioned I bought the domain pay me
sooner
>> as a result so it's like ah bill me
later was a good idea pay me sooner
would be an even better idea actually
the idea there it still is it's not it's
not terrible because it's not payments
it's lending so think of it this way
Imagine that. Like big companies beat up
small companies all the time to get
better payment terms. Better payment
terms for them, right? It's like so if
I'm GE and you're Eric Torrenberg and
you're a little guy, I'm big GE. I'm
like, I'm going to pay you net 90. So
you invoice me and I pay you 90 days
later. Now you have to pay your
employees. So you go to a bank, you go
to somebody else. You're like, hey, I'm
Eric. Uh, I run this business. Most of
my money comes from GE. They're an
awesome company. They're going to pay me
in 90 days. bank doesn't care, right?
They're just like, "Yeah, we're going to
charge you 15%." Meanwhile, GE can issue
bonds at like, you know, whatever sofur
plus 10 basis points or something. Like
GE is paying 5% for credit. You're
paying 15% for credit, but it kind of
doesn't make sense because your credit
is G's credit, if that makes sense. Now,
there's something called factoring where
you can sell the invoice. You can
actually sell the receivable. That's
somewhat usurious. um that that's very
very actually it's not usurious because
it doesn't like credit laws don't apply
because you're selling a receivable but
I always thought that pay me sooner was
an interesting idea because the whole
economy runs on the fact that like my
business is waiting on payments from you
like the reason why I have to borrow
money is because you don't pay me sooner
uh or other way around sorry I don't pay
you sooner and yeah so but yes we didn't
we didn't pursue that
>> there there's some healthy businesses
these days in both accounts payable
financing and accounts receivable
financing so it's
This is it's not a bad idea, but the
revenue opportunity despite being an
unregulated lending space is seemingly
lower than the one in consumer because
the convenience factor is something that
every participant understands and there
are plenty of players that'll offer you
a slightly cheaper chart which is also
the root origin of why a $40 trillion
wire to Roana is going to be uh
>> not very profitable business whoever
processes it.
>> Yes. What what's what's another idea
that you're surprised uh does not exist
yet that you were thinking at some
point, hey, the world obviously should
work this way? There's, you know, an
obvious opportunity here and for
whatever, you know, conflation of
reasons just hasn't happened yet or or
to use uh you know, Mark's quote, there
are no bad ideas, only early ideas. Is
is there something else that you're
surprised has not happened yet?
You know, we're forever in search of the
great way to pay biometrically, and it
manifests itself more in movies where
people's thumbs and eyeballs get removed
for authentication purposes.
And yet, like, we're still paying with
chips. By the way, the card payment
interface is the singular best user
interface ever created. And it it's not
something that people haven't tried to
do better. remember even before PayPal,
there was this wand that I think
Mastercard and one of the gas um
uh refueling station networks produced
this thing where you could like wave
this wand next to a gas station and
payment is secured and you can fuel your
car. And when I saw it, I'm like, "Oh my
god, this is obviously going to take
over credit cards." And it didn't. And
there actually therein lies a really
interesting lesson in payments
innovation in general. There's some
unobvious a priority but clear
opposeriori version of critical mass and
if you don't reach it you're going to
fail like there's not really a okay
outcomes in payments. You either get
there and everyone needs to have your
widget or your network or your whatever
or it's just going to go into the uh the
time. And this is a fine example of a
thing that actually made a lot of sense.
Like of course you want to have a little
wand on your car keys to just sort of
wave and get refueled, but it's just a
little bit faster, not a lot faster than
the credit card you have in your pocket.
And that just works. And so I I keep on
waiting for some completely different
way of authenticating the payer to the
device and like other than the mobile
phone, we haven't done better.
>> Amazon actually just discontinued the
whole thumb payment at Whole Foods.
>> They actually It's not a thumb payment.
It's like it's the palm. The palm. Yeah.
>> I loved it. I I would literally go to
Whole Foods next to whatever hotel I'd
be staying in.
>> I was sad that they got rid of it. I
know. I used to use it, too.
>> It's actually not even faster. It's just
fun.
>> I know. It's probably slower.
>> It is slower. It's like tell me my
fortune and these grapes.
>> The fortune is you owe me money. Yes.
That is that is the only fortune that
you ever get. Well, that that was I mean
I think I called it thumb by by uh by
accident just given the the almost uh
almost name of a firm.
>> That's right.
when when sort of the crypto industry
was was becoming popular or when you
know some of the major projects uh were
were starting in in the space did that
were there parts of that that seemed
exciting to you or realization of a you
know long-held uh sort of dream or did
it feel hey orthogonal or just not
really
>> so I I'm frequently late to trends like
I'm not the world's earliest adopture of
majority of things I encounter
>> I feel like PayPal is pretty early right
Well,
sort of. Um, to give you full context
for PayPal, I really wanted to build
something very specific and quite
different from PayPal uh that operated
on very low power chips. And to do that,
I needed to work out how to make
cryptographic primitives work on a very,
very low power chip. And we did. And
then we promptly realized that it really
couldn't do very much other than encrypt
some very very small amounts of data and
small amounts of data that need to be
encrypted and decrypted quickly that
kind of leads you to payments which is
how PayPal came about. But right before
all of that began I went to the
windown/bank bankruptcy party for
DigiCash which was the original
granddaddy of all digital payments. And
uh it was sort of a somber affair. I was
on Stanford University grounds and there
was like you know pouring out of the 40s
and a bunch of very sadl looking cyber
punks telling each other how the age of
digital payments is not upon us and uh
so in that sense we were very late when
sort of I was listening to these people
talk whose idea was crushed it was blind
signatures and David Ch was somewhere he
was actually not present but he was
roaming the uh streets of Palo Alto
despondent because his brilliant idea
and a truly brilliant one was you know
basically being proven to be not having
a a product market fit. Uh and then we
promptly soon thereafter started PayPal
and uh I went to some cryptography
related conference and presented you
know a new idea in digital payments and
was literally booed off stage because it
was not nearly as secure. It was
certainly not anonymous and the the big
innovation of PayPal was what if we
don't care about anonymity at all. In
fact, people don't. They just need to
pay for their coffees or their, you
know, online purchases. And um in in
that sense, um I feel like we were again
very late to that game. The game had
played out like all the enthusiasts had
left the building. Uh and so
cryptocurrency,
not to be confused with cryptography.
uh when so I I read the original Bitcoin
paper and thought, "Wow, that's a really
clever way of solving the Byzantine
general problem. I sort of as all the uh
math cryptography nerds was impressed
with the approach, but I not think for a
second it would become a currency or a
payment method and etc. And I'm not
convinced it's a payment method now and
it's been quite some time, but as
currency and commodity and a store of
value goes, it's certainly proven to be
extraordinarily successful." So I think
the
as I watched uh cryptocurrencies
expand and and become a thing and more
and more of a thing, the use cases are
coming out now. We're, you know, stable
coins are upon us and that's certainly a
collection of very clear uses, but none
have, in my opinion, come close to
breaching the
I'm going to use this to buy a cup of
coffee, which is kind of that's the
canonical and most important, I would
argue, use case for old forms of
payments. So, as currencies go, as store
value goes, fascinating.
You know, when was the last time you
spent a Bitcoin or a Satoshi on anything
actually important? You know, putting
aside people who make it a point of
spending it just to sort of prove the
point wrong
>> and and it's the most important um that
buying coffee is the most important
metric because of just the the volume of
it because the frequency, the practical,
>> there's always an opportunity to use
another form of payment delivery device
to satisfy a basic need. So, if you're
sort of contemplating a $40 trillion
transfer, you'll spend a lot of time
figuring out the secure way, the the
fast way, the cheap way, etc. If you're
passing through your nearby bagel shop
and you need a cup of coffee, if your
cryptocurrency wallet passphrase is too
long, you're going to look for change in
your pocket. And if you don't have it,
you'll pull out a debit card or credit
card. So user interface as the payment
amount diminishes it takes over
cost takes over everything. Basically
convenience just trumps everything else
as the total amount you're trying to
send goes down.
>> Yeah.
I I want you to take us both back to me
memory lane. It's the beginning of a
firm and how you guys navigated the idea
maze of of what would eventually become
a firm.
Um,
you go here.
>> Well, hopefully our stories match.
>> Yeah, we should put us in three
questions for like no separate route.
This this is like the prisoner's
dilemma, right? It's just like ask if
our stories match, we have to we get to
leave. If they don't match, then we have
to stay here all day. Um, so my
recollection was um I ran this company
Trial Pay, which did um alternative
payments for digital goods. So, you
don't want to pay for throwing a sheep
or doing something on some silly social
game, something that was not hard,
valuable, or fun.
>> Who would do such?
>> Who would who would do such a thing?
But, you know, you're buying coins in
Farmville or you're doing something.
You're buying poker chips, virtual poker
chips. Of course, you don't want to pay
get it for free if you sign up for
Geico. There's a lot of economic value
to Geico. You don't really care if you
use Progressive or Geico. Oo, I can get
Farmville coins if I switch to Geico or
get a credit card or sign up for
Netflix. So, that's what we did. And uh
I I was uh somewhat persuasive and
annoying. Probably more annoying than
persuasive. So signed up every other
social gaming company. Um except for
this one called Slide. And uh Max ran
proudly or unproudly ran Slide. And uh I
went to the Allen & Company conference
which I almost didn't go to because my
wife was very very pregnant. So this was
in March of 2009. It's like the first
week of March. My son was born March
28th, 2009, but her due date was March
16th. So like I'm not going to go to
this conference. And then uh the the
Allen guys were like, "This is a very
good conference. You should really go."
I was like, "My wife's very pregnant."
He's like, "You should go to the
conference. If she goes into labor,
we'll fly you back." I was like, "All
right, that sounds good. I'm going." So
I went [snorts] to the conference. I
think we met there briefly. Uh
successfully did not persuade you. U but
then I think I followed up with a note
in Russian.
>> Yes. Um, and this wouldn't have worked
today because now obviously I would have
used Gemini or you know you know chat
GBT to write this probably somewhat
riddled with grammatical flaws Russian
note actually that that probably would
have given it away of not being chat
GPT. It wouldn't have passed it would
have passed panggram but I took Russian
in in high school and college worked
there lived there for a while um and I
think you were like why do you speak
Russian? I think that was the response
but then we just became friendly. Uh I
think I you you sold to Google so I
could not ever convince slide to become
a client of of trial pay sadly. Um but
uh I I seem to recall you had like a
tweet like I'm looking for something to
do. Any idea? And that was like my
reason to reach out and I think we we
had coffee at the forbidden building at
Google. Remember how like there was one
Google building that no guests were
allowed at but you just didn't care. Um
statute of limitations were [laughter]
so they can't.
>> You're revealing all my secrets.
>> Yes. Exactly. Because I know how much
you love Vic. Um, so, so, [laughter] so
we we had coffee there and then that's
where this Yeah, we were talking about
Bimley later, but it was like, you know,
my recollection was it's really hard to
pay for something on a mobile phone.
Mobile phones are becoming more
ubiquitous. We should have a way of
solving the pajama problem of you're
upstairs in your pajamas, you want to
buy something, your credit card is
downstairs, how do you pay? Meanwhile,
not just are mobile phones ubiquitous,
but social networks are ubiquitous. And
maybe there's a new underwriting
mechanism of kind of going back to the
old general store from like the 1800s of
it's like you show up in the general
store, you don't have cash, like both
literally and figuratively. You don't
have it on you, but you don't even have
it, you know, back home. But you run the
general store and you're like, "Okay,
Max, I got you. Don't worry about it."
But today, you're just like a cookie and
an IP address, so I don't really know
who you are. Or if you go to Walmart
offline, it's like, you know, you get
greeted by the very nice greeter. I
don't think they have them anymore, but
like you get greeted by the nice greet.
they have no idea who you are. You can't
do the general store thing. But if you
have 500 friends on Facebook, this was
wrong, by the way, but if you have 500
friends on Facebook and they all have,
you have a thousand pictures that you've
uploaded, you're probably a low credit
risk. And if you're not looking for
credit, this is the key thing. It's like
a lot of credit offers are sent out
proactively. So, you have an 800 FICO. I
know that you have $14,000 that's
revolving for some reason on your
Capital One card. I'm going to send you
a customized mailer saying, "Why don't
you go refinance with me, Bank of
America?" But if you go on Google and
you say like, "I'm out of money. Need
money, need money, credit, credit,
credit," like you're probably a bad
credit risk. So, kind of going back to
the general store concept, people that
aren't looking for credit that might not
have their wallet with them, kind of
make it like the 1800s and pay with your
identity. That that was kind of how I
remembered it. Yeah, I think that that
that matches. Uh the
to add a little bit more color to it. So
the year at Google was definitely
a challenge in a sense that I was still
coming to terms that I ran for like over
5 years a company in social media that I
had no business running. Like I I worked
very hard.
had a financially very positive outcome
for a lot of people, but ultimately it
never sort of scratched the sort of
entrepreneurial itch that I thought I
was I was scratching. And so one of the
things that happened during that year,
I spent a lot of time soulsearching like
what am I supposed to do next with my
life? I was going to start a company,
but you know, maybe maybe I should be
more thoughtful about what company I'm
going to start next. And my wife, who's
pretty much always right, said, "You
know,
the hardest you've ever worked and the
happiest you were was during the
anti-fraud days at PayPal, like when you
nearly died, or we nearly died. She was
there as well." Um,
those were the days when you looked
exhausted, but you actually were
obviously very happy. And you know, I
you know, she was telling me, "I know
you swore off doing financial services.
I know you're never going to touch
payments again, but just this once. Give
give it a chance. And that that actually
had some influence as to my
responsiveness, too, because you're
working on a payments company. And part
of my reluctance to deal with trial pay
was like, I can't handle another near
payments company. Like I I went into
social media for a reason. I don't want
anything to do with this stuff. And so,
as I was slowly getting reeled back into
working on payments,
we started talking about this. The sort
of a social BML was one of the sort of
short hands we used. discussing what it
would be. Um, the general store analogy
was interesting because at the same
time, I can't remember which one of us
knew this cuz you also speak Japanese
and this this could have been the thing
you told me, but I remember reading
about social credit in different
economies. There's a notion of just pay
me later or pay me next time in Israeli
grocery stores, which is still common
today. If you're checking out an Israel,
apparently in a small enough town, you
can just show your bag to the cashier.
they'll remember and then they'll get
you next time if you forgot your money.
This is even more formalized in Japan
where until very recently you would give
your business card to the storekeeper
even if they didn't know you. If you had
a business card, they would write what
you bought on the back of it and that
was your total. And the notion of like
you just put it on my tab is a thing
that's you know obviously fairly
American concept and so on. And so we
were converging on this. Uh I was
talking to a startup at the time.
ascouch just learning about the industry
that was trying to build a social credit
score kind of modeling it on the Chinese
social score which is used for a lot
more than than credit obviously. So we
were swirling around this idea of
payments and solving the I don't have my
credentials with me but I still need to
get through this. Like another sort of
metaphorical version of this was I'm
watching TV. did this really cool ad
back in the day when people had
advertisements in between things in TV.
Uh, and I really want the thing that was
promised to me at the price that it was
promised to me, but I could do it on my
phone, but I'm definitely not going to
get off my bed. And so, like what if
there's some area under the curve that
you can capture by bringing these um
transactions closer in time and
improving conversion obviously. And so,
that that's the kind of the the swirly
origin story. Um,
a lot of it I think the two of us had a
slightly different version of what would
be fun. So I think you as a payments guy
you were mostly thinking like let's go
do some payments stuff. As a person
recovering from doing lots of machine
learning in a service of social media
which was you know good and well but
wasn't really what I was meant to do and
lusting for the days of doing machine
learning to fight fraud. My mo was I
just want to build a really cool credit
score and then someone else will take
care of payments like lending payments.
Don't really know anything about it. And
I've done payments. Don't need to do
lending. But building a really cool
score that would be amazing because I
remember just the reams of data we had
access to at PayPal. We could maybe get
some data. Maybe we could buy some data.
We could mine Facebook for data. I'm
trying to get in touch with Mark
Zuckerberg to see if he might give me
some of his data. And so a lot of that
was sort of in my head while you were
like I just want to close some
transactions. I think that that maybe if
there's any difference between the
motivations you were much more motivated
by let's go find a merchant.
>> Well but the similar motivation was like
you know trial pay I think we were in
the throws of selling to PayPal but then
they they left me at the altter not your
PayPal the many many generations later
PayPal. Um and I was like I never want
to start a company again. This is so
painful. I and then you you had been in
that in the throws of that as well. So,
it was also like let's get this thing
going. Um, and we'll hire other Well,
but then you introduced me to Nathan uh
and Jeff um and we kind of formally
incorporated, but I I also like the
other thing that I distinctly remember
and you'll you remember this in a very
negative light because it's PHP, but uh
we had a meeting this I I kind of think
of the origin as being the Allen and
Company conference in 2012.
>> Oh, yeah. I I don't I don't find it a
negative thing.
>> No, no, I know. But it was funny. So, so
we have this meeting like so, uh, we're
going through the the list with, uh,
son, remember your your old chief of
staff, right? So, we're going through
the list and it's like, oh, we both know
Jim McCann, who's this very friendly guy
who used to be on all the commercials
for 1800 Flowers. Remember 1800 Flowers,
you can order flowers. Order it right
now for me or whatever the commercial
was. So, uh, we ping him to get a
breakfast meeting. It was like 200
person conference. Anybody can be with
anybody, but it's like, hey, why don't
we have breakfast? And I I pulled like
an allnighter making this demo um in
PHP. Yeah, I basically like cloned. It's
just funny like a I could do this in 5
seconds now, but I I I cloned 1800
Flowers site um and then made a whole
like pay with your identity. So you do a
checkout like add the dozen roses to,
you know, make up for the bad stuff that
I did. Sending it to my wife, click pay.
Oh shoot, I don't have my my my payment
card with me. I can pay with Facebook.
What does that do? It does Facebook
connect. It makes sure that I have over
500 friends. And actually Facebook had I
mean to your point, they had a lot of
interesting data. They had their own
internal flags around did they think
this account was fraudulent or not. And
fraudulent for back then was more of
like it was just created not as a real
account. It wasn't a real person because
an account is not a person, right?
Hopefully they're the same thing, but
not necessarily because one person can
have multiple accounts. Um, but if
there's one to one. So, so that was uh
that was our fun demo and then I
remember Jimmy was like, "This is great.
Let's do it."
>> Yeah. So, I
two other colorful points from that. So,
it was a good breakfast. And then in the
middle of it, he goes, "Oh, yeah. We
used to do exactly this thing back in
the day when the service members would
call us and say, "Send me my wife some
flowers." And uh, "No, I don't have my
credit card with me." And like, oh, that
that's fine. Like, you know, thank you
for your service. We'll we'll just get
you on the next one. And he like
intuitively grocked this idea that like
you can absolutely postpay a thing if
you have enough trust. And we were
basically there raising our hands saying
we'll take the responsibility for, you
know, if they don't pay you, it's okay.
We're going to eat it. And uh so he was
like instantly smitten. He he had been a
great proponent of the product and like
a supportive, you know, person
slashpresence in my professional life
ever since that breakfast. And he had
absolutely no reason to trust us other
than like he has some degree of sense
who we were. And it was like you guys
are great. You seem like you really know
what you're doing. Like he was so
excited. We have no idea.
>> Well, then we got handed to uh this what
was his name? He actually now runs a
successful startup. The uh the guy that
was Amit. Yes. Amit Sha.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. So, Amit took over. We implemented
he was very very excited. But and I
remember I I I came up in Microsoft I
think I did this in Microsoft Word or
Excel like here's our pricing sheet. We
need a pricing sheet and I was like why
don't we charge 7%. [laughter]
um like so in in consumer finance for
these things there's a concept of an MDR
and an APR. So merchant discount rate
because you're discounting what you pay
the merchant because you're advancing in
the cash right now. You're not
collecting it until later. So call it a
7% merchant discount rate but I think
there was like some table. I just
literally made this up. Um and then and
then there was an APR. Um but the APR
here there was no APR. It was just MDR.
Um but then nobody like I I showed this
to somebody. I think it was Rob Feifer
actually uh before we hired
>> you had like a real finance employee.
>> Uh yeah. So but but I I showed him this.
He was like free flowers, right? Because
he's like you just didn't have to pay us
back. Um so the the returns were not
fantastic on that.
>> So cynical.
>> Um but uh yeah, I think he literally
said free flowers. It's like this is
this is a great deal free flowers.
>> This is just a generally a very smart
but very cynical guy. So we were not
going to be perturbed by some cynicism.
>> I love route.
>> Uh his sister used to work for me. So I
remember uh interviewing him in the
context of a firm although I think at
the time it was still Expedite.
>> Yeah. It briefly bumped around as
expedite and then we finally renamed it.
>> What was it? It was it was incorporated
as Expedite Software Inc.
>> Yeah, I think that's right.
>> And so how did the idea evolve as you
you know went from there? When did it
start to really get get product market
fit or how did the space play out in the
way that you know
>> every startup
has the 40 years in a desert like it's
just a a given like if it's worth
talking about expost I mean some some
people just like quit too early or you
know something happens to to destroy it
but I've never run into a company where
people start a company and they just
like hit product market fit and 24 hours
later they're just selling and you know
everything's going swimmingly. So you
always have this period where like kind
of still makes sense to show up to work,
but you don't really know if it's going
to end in like a great nothing. And we
were definitely meandering through the
great nothing period for a while. After
100 flowers, we had a sort of non-stop
interactions with said Ahmed, who was
never happy with the conversion rate,
with the user interface, and he was
mostly right. like he he was kind of a
grumpy demanding guy but he knew what he
was talking about from the product and
financials perspective and he was
definitely not going to pay 7%. Uh and
so uh we were sort of limping through
that. We're generating a little bit of
volume, but among other things, the
notion of, hey, you can pay us later
showed up after you selected the
flowers. And so he would say, "Look, you
guys are cannibalizing my credit card
volume. If I charge if I were charged
nothing for it, of course, I'd send you
more transactions, but you're charging
me more than credit cards, so it's it's
a dumb idea. like I don't want to pay
anything for it at all. You know, you
guys ought to be ashamed of yourself
basically. And we were sort of trying to
convince other merchants, but we had one
merchant that was essentially saying,
"Yeah, I mean, these guys are nice guys,
but it's kind of worthless." And so it
it was it was going nowhere fast. And
then we had another friend, somebody
named Nils, who ran a company called
Beautylish, which is kind of still
around, but they were selling online
cosmetics and beauty products. And the
only difference that Beautylish
did as they implemented expedite, I
think by then it may have already I
think it was named the firm by then was
that they told their shoppers upfunnel
basically as they were selecting their
shampoos and and perfumes that you could
pay
in three installments or 30 days later
or or whatever it is we were trying to
sort of do. then and that had an instant
30% increase in conversion and that was
the oh we know what this is this isn't
an alternative this isn't actually
solving the pajama problem it is solving
my budget is this but if I could pay
over multiple periods of time it would
expand a lot and so the second we sort
of understood the very beginnings of
that notion we turn it right around into
a sales campaign and very quickly found
a bunch of smallish brands primarily
direct to consumers who could not care
whether we charged them 1%, 5% or 12%.
Because they were trying to grow their
top line and telling their shoppers
that, hey, you could pay for this over
time instead of having to cough up the
cash right now. It was transformative.
And so I would literally get these love
letters from merchant CEOs saying, and
I'm still friends with a lot of them,
like early adopters. Most of these
people have now either sold their
businesses or the business has failed or
they've gone on to do something else.
But I still run into people who were
like there's this woman named Tracy from
Tradzy. Tradzy.com was a
>> Oh, yeah. I just saw her. Yeah. She
She's wonderful. And she was an early
advocate for us
>> because her business literally
>> I forgot about her.
>> She would email me screenshots of her
dashboards and say, "This is the affirm
effect. Here's a 35% pop you guys caused
for me. Like, please do more."
>> Well, there there was a solution to the
pajama problem. And then it was also all
the mattress companies.
>> Oh, yes.
>> That that that was
>> that was another that was the big one. I
just remember it's like, you know, wait,
there's a company called Purple and
there's a company called Casper. It's
just like they just kept coming out of
the woodwork and that was
transformative. And I remember actually
we were talking about this in the
context of like how can you charge a
high MDR and get away with it? That
sounds bad. Not get away with it, but
like actually show sufficient value to
the merchant. The highest MDRs are
actually for-profit education
institutions. Mhm.
>> So, some of them are like 50 like I mean
I I don't like these guys in particular,
but like University of Phoenix.
>> Um, so there's the private equity firm
Apollo, but there's also like this
holding company of all these for-profit
institutions called Apollo Group or
Apollo something. And University of
Phoenix, I think, is the biggest one.
And they just assume that most people
aren't going to pay. And the the gross
margins are so high because it's an
online course. They're like, "Okay, you
could take 50%." Right? you're stuck
with the receivables on the back end,
which goes back to the fraud fighting
that Max was talking about before
because the gross margins of the
mattress, like these mattresses, I don't
know if you ever bought one. It's pretty
cool because they didn't actually ship
you a mattress that looks like this. It
rolls out. So, you get this like
cylinder. It's pretty small.
>> Some of them are boxes.
>> Some of them are boxes, but some of them
it's like you just open it and then it
just like it's like one of those old
like toys that you'd put in like your
bath and then it would expand or
something. It's that was like the
mattress. So they had very very high
gross margins. So therefore a lot more
flexible on the MDR and more importantly
nobody wants like you're in your pajamas
on your uncomfortable mattress. You
don't want to spend $1,200 on a mattress
but if it's like 30 like it once you
subdivided it just has a massive
increase of conversion rate.
>> Yeah. There's a couple of other sort of
technical things that are probably worth
tapping into in in that story but that
that that was the next big leap. So, the
mattresses was the precursor to the
great expansion into DDC brands, which
I'm sure we'll touch on. But before we
get there, a firm briefly flirted with
being a payment provider to the online
educational facilities,
>> which we ran out of kicking and
screaming because the reason they're
willing to pay these enormous MDRs is
because the quality of education is
largely terrible. Yeah. So, the reason
people don't pay most of the time isn't
because they're like, "Oh, I thought
about it. Now that I have a master's
degree in basket weaving, I just don't
want to pay for it." See, it turns out
my degree is worth nothing. Like, why
did I sign up for this ridiculous thing?
And so, we were, if you go back to sort
of, you know, things like um what is it
called? General Assembly. Is that their
whole sort of class of these like we
will teach you how to code? Another PEI
thing like learn how to code. Just ask
Chad GPT to code for you. But uh back in
the day when it was still important to
learn how to code, but you didn't really
want to go to college for it. You just
want to take a six week course. There
were plenty of the sort of University of
Phoenix clones that
>> Academy.
>> Yeah. There's all the all these guys.
And uh we saw that trend and thought,
"Oh my god, like these people are
willing to subsidize education, which is
cool and on mission for us." And uh yet
the loss rates to consumer
dissatisfaction were so high we lasted
like a half a year in that space. But
back to mattresses. So the thing that's
really powerful about direct to consumer
or you can think of them as vertically
integrated businesses. So there's some
factory in Brooklyn presumably or who
knows where.
>> China.
>> China. Uh I thought the mattress guys
manufactured locally because
>> I don't know but they were all in Utah.
Remember that?
>> Yeah. I feel like it was like there was
like a Utah mattress town or something.
But I think they just all originated
there. Casper is in New York or was it
purple I think was in and then there
were like other purples that were
>> I think one of the weirder things the
manufacturing was actually all
consolidated so they ultimately sort of
paid very little for these mattresses
that were kind of all the same. I mean
don't want to reveal any industry
secrets but memory foam is memory foam.
>> Uh anyway and so they their primary
value or their their their value
equation was really interesting. So,
first of all, they bought this memory
foam in a box and sort of compressed and
shipped it to you with a cool effect.
The margin there were gargantuan because
you are in fact just sort of taking
petroleum and turning it into foam. But
the other thing is the replacement
cycle. And this actually goes to a I
think a Harvard Business Review article
that came out right before Casper was
founded. And all these guys, all these
really entrepreneurial people read the
same article which essentially said
this, people replace mattresses once
every seven years. If you're the company
that sells that mattress,
it is the most important thing in the
world. And if you miss it, the next
opportunity is seven years from now. But
the margins on mattresses even before
the sort of the foam and the everything
else are like 80% or some some
eyepopping number. And so suddenly four
or five companies were born from that
article basically saying like, "Oh my
god, so if we just figure out how to
market a mattress that you will either
shorten your replacement cycle, so you
you buy the next mattress 6 years
instead of seven years from the last one
or you just decide this mattress is the
best mattress or the coolest one or the
one that pops out of a box." that is
like oh you know there's so much money
in it and one it resulted in a
saturation of mattress industry
obviously but more to the point it
created this enormous premium on I will
just compel you to buy a mattress by any
means necessary so telling you I will
give you a three-year loan at no
interest at all powered by a firm of
course is like a small price to pay and
a cool marketing campaign and and and
and so that was there were multiple
events like this in a firm's history
where we saw an opportunity for the
merchant to significantly contribute to
the MDR which allowed us to eliminate
the APR. In other words, consumer got a
true 0% loan. The backdrop to this
that's actually really really important
to understand and one of my sort of you
know things that I rage against have and
and will continue to until it's made
illegal or eliminated by by other means
is the fake 0% law. So if you ever have
gone to a, you know, fill in your
favorite department store, there is a
sign somewhere these days somewhat less
prominent that says get a branded credit
card from fill in the blank 0% APR.
There's an asterisk next to the zero
which says something along the lines of
assuming you make a purchase for the
next 12 months or 24 months, if you're a
penny short or a day late paying your
principal, the interest acrru
retroactively to the beginning of time.
Basically, the day you got that card,
you swiped it for $1,000. You wake up
and you owe $3,000 two years later. So,
this is called the deferred interest
credit card. And a huge opportunity we
tapped into
directly from that rage was this idea,
well, our 0% is going to be a real zero.
When you go to buy the inflatable
mattress or the mattress from a box,
you're going to get a 0% loan. And even
if you're a month late or a year late,
we're not going to change the price
because we are so sick and tired of
these ridiculous people who are lying to
you about zero with an asterisk. It will
never be an asterisk on a firm zero.
That that is the origin story of why we
don't charge lead fees. We don't do
deferred interest. all the sort of
gimmicks and gotchas that the industry
loves to throw at people. We we've run
away from all of that primarily as a
point of like you know what when you
decide to do this for three years with
us you will never get screwed. You will
never be surprised to the negative and
so that that was another sort of big
bounce up point and then then every
mattress company was like oh wow like
these guys are doing it we should do the
same thing. Okay so fast forwarding a
bit a lot of people hear a firm today
and you know one quick thing they think
is you know buy now pay later. What does
this not fully encapsulate or what does
this miss about the company today? It's
in its entirety. One of the things in
the email thread that I just reread in
the origin origin of a firm was your
claim that advertising and payments are
converging which was the thesis behind
trial pay thesis behind a bunch of
different things actually a failed
project within PayPal called PayPal
shops where I was trying to personally I
built this thing where was trying to
remarket what you just bought. That
affirmation should give us a sense for
what we might buy next and you know all
that. And all these things by the way
have turned out to be true. Like there
was just you know 15 20 30 years before
their time. But a firm more and more
today is means for merchants to not just
satisfy demand. So somebody comes in and
says look I'm going to buy this thing
but my budget is this big. I won the
shoes and I love a bag but I'm and a
firm is there say actually we can help
you finance this on transparent terms. a
lot of times, a third of the time, uh,
no interest at all. You should get the
bag and the shoes. It's safe. That that
that is the brand promise of a firm and
it works tremendously well. You know,
tens of billions of dollars a year
worth.
That is now becoming more and more about
creating a platform for merchants to
tell their shoppers, hey, we are
launching a new thing. We have this
desirable new product we are selling.
We've transacted with roughly 50 plus
million Americans alone and we're now
live in four countries and and growing
pretty quickly. And so we have shifted
to just satisfying demand to helping
merchants create or guarantee demand.
And the convergence of payments and
advertising is upon us. Although 15
years later predicted it,
>> you're too early with travel pay. I'm
certainly too early with PayPal.
>> Well, the the other side I remember
maybe it was in that thread or not. I
should I should find that email. But
most companies have very high customer
acquisition cost. And like the joke that
I make now as a VC is that when I see
90% of consumer companies, I'd kind of
rather buy Google stock or Facebook
stock because that's where all the
customers come from. And I distinctly
remember many many conversations around
how do we have negative CAC, right? And
like I think to me one of the coolest
things about a firm to this day is it
has negative customer acquisition cost.
I mean, it is paid to acquire a
customer. And there there are some
companies that you would think they look
like this, but they don't because
they're basically white labeling
something. But going back to the
mattresses, um, let's just say that
you're late on one of your payments.
Casper, the friendly white ghost
mattress company, because Casper is a
white ghost, doesn't want to go or cat
or something. We had a cat named Casper
when I was growing up. They don't want
to send you a dunning notice saying
like, "Get off my mattress. You haven't
paid me back." They want that to be a
third party versus other companies where
yes, you know what is the difference?
What B2B TOC is a really interesting
category. It's business to business to
consumer. I tried doing this with trial
pay because it's like all right, you're
playing a Zinga game. Go get uh free
coins if you sign up for Geico powered
by trial pay. Nobody knew who the hell
trial pay was. So we we actually tried
sending messages to consumers like you
know we got I think we got blocked by
our email provider because nobody we we
actually had a right to email these
customers but they had no idea who we
were whereas actually having a financial
relationship with 50 million people with
negative CAC. I mean it really is not to
pet but it's incredible like it's so
hard to do and we never see anything
like this in the venture land or you
know like because yeah there are lots of
companies that can get to scale. I mean
Casper got to scale but lots of CAC lots
of CAC and that's why a lot of these
business models they tend to degrade
over time because all the economic value
goes to Google and Facebook so if you
can have negative CAC and then you can
launch other products as well right
because you actually own the customer
and most important the brand wants you
owning the customer like this is what I
didn't get right at trial pit like Zinga
didn't want me owning their customer
Netflix didn't want me owning their
customer I just connected the two but um
a firm the the merchants She wants you
to own the customer.
>> It's very you already have a burden of
supporting your product and dealing with
unsatisfied customers or technical
support issues or whatever. A company
that tells you 12 times for your long
loan or 39 times, you know, if it's a
three and a half year loan, hey, you're
late or you got to got to make your
payment or all the communications that
come from your lender is just another
type of burden that the brand is kind of
like, you know what, a firm you guys can
handle this. This would be great. And so
the the relationship with the customer
is a key component of the foundation of
a firm and the our ability to develop
new products is is really built on that.
One of the other really sort of cool to
sort of going all the way back to the
credit scoring thing.
So we are the only company in the
industry really there's plenty of
competitors who are trying and some some
degree of success but mostly not really
who will go into these longerterm loans
and by longer I don't mean mortgage for
you know 15 plus years but like three
and a half years is a fairly long period
of time relative to the average bailator
which is like 6 weeks and to do that you
have to underwrite like you can't
shortcut the I'll just look at your FICO
score or I'll just sort of you know I'll
look at your Facebook friends like none
of that works you actually have to do a
real very sophisticated degree of u
machine learning work. There are two
cool things about it. It's hard to do
and so it's just hard to compete with us
on that front. But the other side is it
gives you 39 shots on gold or 12 shots
on gold to tell this consumer as you
send them billing notices and as you
have conversations with them as they pay
you to upsell them on a new service. And
so these long-term loans, which are
actually quite hard to manage and quite
hard to maintain reasonable default
rates and and delinquency rates on, is
the price you pay as a provider of
financing to upsell consumers on more
and more services. And so our our
business has been fueled by these
long-term products,
even though they are probably the the
most challenging part of payments.
>> Yeah. You know, we've been covering some
a firm history. While we're doing a
historical episode, I also want to ask a
question about PayPal history.
>> [snorts]
>> I'll keep us straight [laughter]
and
>> you know um there's been you know a book
came out founders recently there's been
sort of a lot of uh you know revisiting
of of of PayPal both in its impact as u
you know pioneer in sort of uh you know
payments and and and fintech but also in
terms of the the people uh that came out
of it and sort of the it it feels like
the you know highest concentration of um
highest hit rate of people who would go
on to do incredible things. The only
comparable thing I could think of today
is it's not even a company is the deal
fellowship or or something. I can't
think of a comparable company to PayPal
today. I'm curious if you you can um and
you know all with uh or many with
extremely strong strengths but also you
know very strong personalities and some
strong weaknesses as well. And so I'm
curious if there's something you think
that is goes as that story is being told
of both of its impact in the industry,
you know, how early was uh and and sort
of the people that came out of it. if
there's something that's
underappreciated or you think not quite
groed or any any additions you want to
make to how we perceive that that
company in that time period
>> sort of an old answer and a new answer
to this question which I've you might
you might expect I've answered once or
twice before u so the the canonical
answer that I gave in a book which by
the way is very good so there there have
been many much ink spilled on the
history of PayPal the founder is
actually a very good book like and part
of it is because it's well written but
part of it is because Jimmy the guy who
wrote it interviewed every single
character in the story extensively. He
spent a lot of time talking to all of us
and so it's at the very least grounded
in fact. Um so the the answer I gave for
his research was as we were interviewing
certainly the early team and even the
later team we kept on selecting four
entrepreneurs. We would ask like one of
the stock questions I would ask so what
are you going to do after PayPal? And
the answer that I welcomed the most was
oh this is the last one I'm going to
start my own afterwards. So this notion
like oh if you're coming in here to kind
of get your final graduate degree in
entrepreneurship of course we'd love to
have you like you know if you're you're
that smart you're that good and you're
that ambitious you know please come
along and so that's kind of the why I
think so many people that came out of
PayPal proceeded to start companies and
like literally you know hot second after
we all dispersed YouTube and Yelp and
Peter's first major fund and LinkedIn
and so that was not an accident we for
attracting entrepreneurs by design. The
other part that I think is actually not
been talked about and maybe subtle and
sort of my own cut of this, but we knew
the people in the room intimately like
we literally, you know, exchanged firm
by hanging out in these sweaty rooms,
brainstorming, screaming at each other
and spending a lot of time as
whiteboards and declaring the other
person's ideas idiotic and and so on. we
knew the the true version of that
person, the sort of the extremely
I don't know uh the the the ultra
philosophical Peter Teal and the uh you
know go all in every time Elon Musk and
the
these days uh gubernatorial uh David
Sax, you know, all these people like
they all have kind of the the present
the presentation layer and then there's
like the kind of what they are like in a
dinner party and then like what are they
when they're really stressed out and
just like head hurts, don't know what to
do, and we have a real problem we need
to solve. So, if you know kind of the
true base version of who we all are as
you watch one of these people go for
something really big like Elon taking
humanity to Mars, which is
extraordinary. And yet, you know, he's a
human being. Like, I've seen him sweaty
and tired and grumpy at the company
kitchen a thousand times. or Peter when
he is in his doubt and calls me from
some fundraising trip saying, "I think
we might run out of money." You know,
they're not gods. You know, they're
humans. And that inspires you to
actually like, you know what, if that
guy who's just a normal dude, I spent a
lot of time with him, he's normal.
And he's going for this big of an idea,
I should do the same. I I should I
should strive, too. And so, I think the
combination of these are very ambitious
people. We all wanted to be
entrepreneurs, but we also knew each
other when we were young and filled with
doubt, which many I think still are. Uh
I think that that sort of gives you a
confidence that it's not all, you know,
bed of roses. It's it's it's paved with
uh with with with with bumpy parts.
>> Is there anything we didn't get to that
you want to make sure that we get to
while we're here?
>> I'm probably less optimistic about
agentic shopping and I'm very optimistic
about aentic payments. Yeah,
>> I think the the notion of robots will
buy our
Friday night outfits is misguided. We
want to know what we look like long
before the robot delivers it to your
door. But I think the friction, this
notion of so the best user interface
ever created is the credit card. This
may actually be finally up for
renegotiation because agents are in fact
smarter than pieces of plastic and even
pieces of plastic with rewritable chips.
And so I think that's uh a lot of
conversation around aentic commerce is
probably looking 20 degrees off where
you know how can I convince you to just
trust a robot to buy the right thing. I
don't want to like I love buying bike
parts and I spend way too much time
looking at two slightly different bike
parts because I just you know have to
participate in the purchase [sighs]
but [snorts] the part where like okay
that one the end right now that one is
the beginning where you pull out your
wallet or you and so I think we we're
we're about to see some interesting
innovation in payments user interface.
>> So I can I ask a question on that? So,
um I mostly agree, but I think it
depends on there's like the I need to
research what to buy.
>> Mh.
>> Where AI is just yet another tool at
your disposal. Like you ask your
friends, that's what I'm if it's a bike
part, I'm asking you. I'm also asking
AI. I'm asking both of you. But now I
have the skew that I want. And I don't
actually care which one of the 19
different places that I get it from. And
I kind of think about the world like you
have people that care more about money
than time. You have people that care
more about time than money.
The way that I kind of think about
ajected commerce, again, none of this is
happening right now. So, it's trying to
prognosticate what's going to happen is
here is the the UPC. Here's the the skew
that I actually want. Go buy it for me
at the lowest cost. It's kind of the
thing that people that have a lot more
time than money do right now anyway. And
like that's why I always point to Camel.
Camel. Camel is like my favorite example
of this because it's one of the top
hundred websites in America that
probably nobody with over $100,000 a
year of income has ever heard of. But
it's it's a way of saying I know what I
want. You're not helping. The robot's
not telling me what bike part to buy,
what telling me what soda to buy. I
know. Just give it to me at the lowest
price. But it takes way too much time.
And sometimes you can just observe one
group of humans that already have
something as table stakes and then
porting that to another group of humans.
I I guess do you think that that form of
agentic commerce because it's actually
related to edgentic payments as well.
>> I have nine different cards. I don't
remember the Amazon Chase issued by
Chase card terms for a nonrest purchase
of something under $500. and if I've
used my whatever. Like it's the same
thing. Like people that care more about
money than time, they will figure that
out. People that care more about time
than money, they probably won't. I think
directionally that'll make sense. I
think the adoption curve is probably
going to be fairly slow. And these
things are always sort of easy to
predict to be very slow. And sort of the
usual adage is well slowly at first, not
always once. I'm I'm not I'm not sure I
I can handicap that. Well, the reason
people don't So, there's plenty of
people who live in this somewhat murky
world of sometimes I have money,
sometimes I have time. And it has more
to do than anything with the price and
the degree of care you put into. I mean,
I don't always just buy bike parts.
Sometimes I buy milk and milk is built.
Where are my bike parts?
I mostly buy parts. Um, but uh the I I
think what really happens for a lot of
people, it's just like, well, yeah, I'll
I'll get the I'll find the cheapest
price, but then I'm not sure how to
handicap the probability of that item
actually showing up at my door at the
time of my desired outcome. Even if I'm
okay buying a some bike part from some
far away land and it's sold from three
different retailers,
I'm going to go with the most reputable
one versus the one that's got profit
promising me the cheapest or sometimes
the fastest. And so I think we're
probably a few steps away from AI
grasping
both the preferences but also
handicapping how these preferences would
change based on the input which may in
fact maybe AI is already there. is just
that you haven't yet trusted your agent
to do as good a job as you would. Like
you can eyeball a side be like that
looks like it was edited in the 90s. I'm
just not quite sure that I'm going to
spend $1,000 for a new cassette or $600,
whatever the cassettes go for these days
in bike cassettes, the rear assembly.
>> Well, Bike Closet is the site that I'm
thinking about that looks like it was
made in the 1990s that will sell you a
very cheap cassette.
>> Uh, exactly. But do you know if they
were used by by someone you know true
teeth rubbed off and all?
>> Uh yeah. So I I think I think we are in
that difficult period where we're still
figuring out. The other thing that you
know just sort of maybe end on a
positive note. The thing that's really
true that no one seems to be celebrating
just yet is
grocery shopping is 100% agentic. Like
for anyone who uses Instacart like you
tell your Instacart shopper go bring me
milk. you don't think twice when they
say, "Oh, yeah, you wanted whole milk
from Organic Valley, but I found some
other brand and here it is." And you're
like, "Oh, of course, like makes sense."
Like, and so the AI inside that
shopper's head is maybe not even as good
as Gemini or ChadB is these days, but
you just sort of say, "I you just you go
through Trader Joe's or Whole Foods or
whatever you're shopping and you figure
it out and it shows up and 99.9% of the
time it is exactly what you want it or
better." And so we are already
conditioned to allow some of these
purchases to be fully outsourced,
payments and shopping and everything
else. And so we're definitely going to
get there. It's just a question of how
soon will we work through the quirks of
like well returning of this wrongly
purchased bike part or waiting for it
forever and not really knowing what's
going to happen to it because it's in
transit but we don't know where it is. I
that may be protracted more protracted
people think.
>> That's a good note to end on. We'll have
to uh get a part two uh at some point
when we talk more about the future. Uh
Max, Alex, thanks so much for